ratespecial.com 2012-03-25

# Privacy Policy - RateSpecial – A Boutique Interactive Agency

## Privacy Policy

### About this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy describes information that we collect from you as part of the normal operation of our service and what may happen to the information we collect.

### Application of this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy applies to RateSpecial and all websites (“Site” or “Sites”) owned and controlled by RateSpecial,LLC. (“RateSpecial”, “we”, or “us”). Please note that this Privacy Policy applies only to Sites owned and controlled by RateSpecial and not to websites maintained by other companies to which we may link.

By registering with us (i.e. through the submission of the information requested, including your personally identifiable information) on this Site or otherwise using or accessing this Site, you agree that the following terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy shall govern our use and disclosure of your personal information. If you do not agree with the terms and conditions of our Privacy Policy, please do not complete any information request forms (i.e., do not register) hosted on this site or otherwise use or access this Site.

This Site is not directed at persons under the age of 18. Persons under the age of 18 must not send any personal information to Ratespecial under any circumstances, including but not limited to name, address or email address.

### Your Privacy is Important to Us

Our Privacy Policy explains what information we obtain on the Site and how we use the information you disclose to us, including how we may provide your information to our Third Party Providers who have expressed a willingness to provide you with the products and services associated with this Site, as well as other products and/or services that we and they believe may be of interest to you.

By entering your contact information, you are authorizing us, or a Third Party Provider, to contact you with exciting new offers and information, via email and automated telephone messages, even if you are listed on a Do Not Call Registry. Users may opt out of the Companies disclosure to such third parties by following the instructions in the opt-out section of this privacy policy. We may also disclose nonpublic personal information about you as permitted by law.

### Who We Are

We are an online consumer service that introduces persons such as yourself to certain of our Third Party Providers who have expressed a general willingness to review your information and determine if they are willing to provide you with the services or products that prompted you to visit our Site, as well as other products and/or services that we and they believe may be of interest to you.

### Information We Collect

The information that we collect includes personal information about you that we or certain of our Third Party Providers consider necessary for performing a preliminary evaluation of your qualifications to receive applicable products and/or services. To the extent that you can order products or subscribe to a service(s), the type of personally identifiable information that may be collected may include: name; address; e-mail address; telephone number; fax number; credit card information; information about your interests in and use of various products, programs, and services; education level; educational interests; home owner status; income; debt level; current mortgage; mortgage rate and the like. To the extent that you are requested and you do submit information about other people, such information will be limited recipient’s name, address, e-mail address, and telephone number.

### Cookies

In addition to the personal information you provide to us, we collect certain information online and offline arising out of your use of our Site, including but not limited to the number and type of offers you have responded to and completed. When you visit our Site, we automatically tracks certain non personally identifiable information with respect to your behavior on the Site through the cookie we place in your browser. This non personally identifiable information may include the Internet address or URL that you just came from and the URL to which you go next; your computer browser information; and your IP address. We use this non personally identifiable information in conjunction with some of the information that you provided to conduct internal research on users’ demographics and behavior and to better understand how to serve users of the Site. The aforementioned information cannot, by itself, be used to gather any personally identifiable information about you, but it will allow us to track the overall effectiveness of our online advertising campaigns. Third parties may also set cookies on or through the service to track Site usage and to track the overall effectiveness of our online advertising campaigns.

We use both session cookies, which terminate when a user closes his/her browser, and persistent cookies, which remain on the user’s computer until manually deleted. You may decline our cookies if your Web browser software permits, although this may prevent you from accessing certain features of the Service.

### Log Files

We track certain non personally identifiable information through server log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp and number of clicks to analyze trends and administer the Site, track user’s movement in the aggregate and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. We use your IP address at times to help identify you as you browse and to gather broad technical and demographic information on who uses the Site. We do not tie server log files to personally identifiable information.

### Web Beacons

We may employ and certain Third Party Providers may employ a software technology called clear gifs (also known as Web Beacons or Web Bugs). Clear gifs help us better manage content through the service by informing us what content and which campaigns are effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics, about the size of a period at the end of a sentence, with a unique identifier. Clear gifs are similar in function to cookies and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In addition, we and certain Third Party Providers may use clear gifs in HTML-based emails. This allows us and the Third Party Provider to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of marketing campaigns by showing how many emails the recipients have opened. We do not tie clear gifs to personally identifiable information.

### How We Use Your Information

We may perform a preliminary validation of any information that you submit to Ratespecial and an evaluation of your qualifications for our Third Party Providers’ products and services. For example, we may compare and review your personal information for errors, omissions, and accuracy based upon past usage and response; or compare your information against other publicly available files; or validate some of the personal information to verify that the information you submitted has a high probability of being valid information.

Based upon your affirmative consent, as evidenced by your clicking on the applicable acknowledgement box and/or your registration on a Site (i.e., your submission of the requested information, including your personally identifiable information), we may use the information you provide to attempt to match you with providers of products and services (for example, using your zip code to check for service providers whose service area covers your location) and/or we may forward the information that you provided directly to certain of our Third Party Providers. We may sell or transfer individual information to other Third Parties for any legally permissible purpose, please see Sharing Your Information.

We reserve the right to collect information about you and store it in connection with other online or offline information we may possess or obtain about you to create a general user profile. This profile may be created by combining your information with other sources of information such as information obtained from public databases, or from your browsing habits surrounding your visit to this Site.

From time to time, we may contact you via e-mail advertising, telephone marketing, direct mail marketing, online banner advertising or other means to inform you of additional opportunities to receive special offers for other services and/or products that we believe may be of interest to you. By providing your contact information when using the Service, you are entering into a business relationship with Ratespecial and are further requesting, and expressly consenting to, being contacted by Ratespecial and our Third Party Providers via telephone, fax, email, surface mail or any other means, at any of your contact numbers or addresses, even if you are listed on any federal, state or other applicable “Do Not Call” list, in order that Ratespecial may provide the services set forth on the Site or for other purposes reasonably related to your service request and the business of Ratespecial, including marketing-related emails. You are under no obligation to accept any service or product offered through these communications.

From time to time, we may send you certain transactional messages relating to the Service, such as service announcements, administrative messages, etc.

To the extent that we collect your credit card information, we will use the information for verification purposes and/or for transmitting the information to the specific Third Party Providers authorized by you for the purpose of completing your requested transaction. Your credit card information will be encrypted during transmission. In addition, by submitting your credit card information to us, you authorize us to verify that your credit card account is valid by charging, and thereafter immediately crediting, a small sum to the card. Such verification may be conducted through a third-party and, in that case, we would share your specific credit card information with this third-party for verification purposes. Notwithstanding the foregoing, we reserve the right to share with third-parties the fact that we have credit card information on file for specific users.

Certain sensitive information such as credit card numbers or other information such as social security numbers and drivers licenses (“Financial Information”) collected on the Site and the associated data are encrypted and protected with SSL encryption software from the time it is captured by our application to the time it is transmitted to our servers. For more information on the encryption and protection of your information, please see How We Protect Your Privacy.

In the event we offer product and/or services where your credit card information is required to process your requested transaction, we may store your credit card information to facilitate your authorized transactions.

## Sharing Your Information

### Third parties

WE MAY USE INFORMATION THAT WE HAVE COLLECTED FOR ANY LEGALLY PERMISSIBLE PURPOSE, INCLUDING SELLING OR TRANSFERRING SUCH INFORMATION AT ANY TIME TO THIRD PARTIES FOR ANY LEGALLY PERMISSIBLE PURPOSE. For example, we may share or sell your personal information with Third Party Providers so that they can contact you and offer you products and/or services that may be of interest to you. This may include e-mail advertising, telephone marketing, direct mail marketing, and online banner advertising to name a few. You are under no obligation to accept any service or product offered by any of our Third Party Providers through these communications. In addition, we may maintain separate e-mail, mailing or phone lists for different purposes based on the information that you submitted and that we maintain. Please keep in mind that if you respond to an offer from one of Ratespecial’s Third Party Providers, you become a customer of that Third Party Provider and are subject to its privacy policy. Further, the Third Party Provider may independently send further communications to you, in which case you will need to contact the Third Party Provider directly if you wish to unsubscribe from future communications from such Third Party Partner.

By providing personal information when using the Sites, you are entering into a business relationship with Ratespecial’s Third Party Providers and are requesting, and expressly consenting to, being contacted by our Third Party Providers via telephone, fax, email, surface mail or any other means, at any of your contact numbers or addresses, even if you are listed on any federal, state or other applicable “Do Not Call” list, in order that our Third Party Providers may provide the services set forth on the Site or for other purposes reasonably related to your service and/or product request to which you have expressed interest and the business of our Third Party Providers, including marketing-related emails.

PLEASE NOTE: submission of YOUR telephone number(s) and a best time to be called is YOUR authorization and request to be called at the telephone number(s) YOU provide.

When you complete a Third Party Partner’s offer displayed through the Site, which may include completing an inquiry form and providing personal information to the Third Party directly, you become a customer of that Third Party and are subject to its privacy policy. You may learn more about any of our Third Party Providers’ privacy policies by visiting our Third Party Providers’ websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of our Third Party Providers’ websites. Further, the Third Party may independently send further communications to you, in which case you will need to contact the Third Party Partner directly if you wish to unsubscribe from future communications from it.

We may disclose your personally identifiable information in response to a subpoena, court order, or other legal process; as well as the transfer or sale of personally identifiable information pursuant to the sale of our business or assets. Should such a combination or acquisition occur, we will require that the new combined or acquiring entity follow this privacy policy with respect to your personal information. If we transfer ownership of the Site to another company, we will notify you by general notice on our Site. In addition to the forgoing, we may also transfer or share non-individualized information, such as summary or aggregated anonymous information about all persons or sub-groups of persons visiting this Site.

We may also transfer or share non-individualized information, such as summary or aggregated anonymous information about all persons or sub-groups of persons visiting this site.

### Service Providers

In order to provide the products or services you have requested, we may disclose the information we collect to companies that perform services on our behalf, such as email communications management firms or call center providers.

### Other Purposes

We may also disclose your personally identifiable information in response to a subpoena, court order, or other legal process; as well as the transfer or sale of personally identifiable information pursuant to the sale of our business or assets. Should such a combination or acquisition occur, we will require that the new combined or acquiring entity follow this privacy policy with respect to your personal information. If we transfer ownership of the site to another company, we will notify you by email or by general notice on our site.

### How We Protect Your Privacy

We protect your privacy in a number of ways. As an initial matter, any Financial Information transmitted to our servers via a secure server is encrypted using SSL technology. SSL is a protocol that transmits your communications over the Internet in an encrypted form. The protocol ensures that the information is sent, unchanged, only to the server you intended to send it to.

Once your Financial Information reaches our server, it is protected by a firewall. In addition to encryption and firewall protections, our Third Party Providers are required to operate in accordance with federal and state laws and regulations, including regulations relating to CAN-SPAM and rules promulgated by the FTC. If we learn that any of our Third Party Providers is breaching our agreement, we will take corrective actions including, if necessary, terminating our relationship with such Third Party Partner.

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security or that all of your private communications and other personal information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. For example, third parties may unlawfully intercept personal data or access our servers and obtain personal data. Therefore, although we use industry standard practices to protect your privacy, we do not promise, nor should you expect that your personal information would always remain private.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can mail us at the address indicated below in the Contact Us section.

### Opting Out

If you wish to opt-out from receiving additional email offers, advertisements and promotions relating to this Site, write to “unsubscribe” or please click on this link to “opt-out”.

If you choose to opt-out, your e-mail address will be added to the suppression files associated with this Site (e.g. Mortgage, Education, Membership Rewards Program, etc.) within ten (10) business days of your request. Thereafter, you should not receive any further email offers, advertisements and promotions from this Site. However you may still receive promotional communications from our Third Party Providers with whom we have shared your information. To stop receiving further communications from these Third Party Providers you will need to contact them directly in order to opt-out. Please note that after we process your request to opt-out from receiving additional email offers, advertisements and promotions from this Site, we will no longer make your information available to our Third Party Providers relating to this Site.

### Notification of Changes to Privacy Policy

We may update this Privacy Policy at any time by posting a new privacy policy on the Site. Be sure to check the current terms of any privacy policy in effect by visiting this Site. By checking the effective date of the policy, you will be immediately alerted on whether the Privacy Policy has been updated. Please note however, that the updated Privacy Policy will go into effect automatically 30 days after initial posting.

From time to time, we may use your information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our Privacy Policy. Please note that if our information practices change at some time in the future, we will use only data collected from the time of the new Privacy Policy amendment forward for those new purposes. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you of such change on our Privacy Policy, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page.

### Contact Us

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact us at: ATTN:RateSpecial Customer Service P.O. Box 26 Pasadena, CA 91102-0026 Fax: 213-799-2464 Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act To the extent Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act, 15 U.S.C. 6802 (the “GLB Act”) may apply to Ratespecial’s services (e.g. mortgage matching service), this Privacy Policy shall serve as your consumer “Privacy Notice” as defined under the GLB Act. Our services shall be deemed to conclude at the time you are matched with our participating service providers or when we notify you that we are not able to match you with any or of participating service providers. Notification of Intellectual Property Rights Infringement We are committed to uphold and respect intellectual property rights. If you are an intellectual property owner and believe that your rights have been infringed by materials on this webpage, please contact our Legal Department. ATTN:RateSpecial Legal Department P.O. Box 26 Pasadena, CA 91102-0026 Please provide the following information in your correspondence to us: your name and contact information, identification of the copyrighted work claimed to be infringed, identification of the material that is claimed to be infringing, and sufficient information for us to locate the material. Please include with your correspondence, (i) a statement that you have a good faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by you (copyright owner), your agent, or the law; (ii) a statement that the information you provided is accurate, and under penalty of perjury, that you are authorized to act on behalf of the owner of the exclusive right that is allegedly infringed.
